Guide to the Thomas Rogers Forbes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Teaching, Research, and Writings, 1930-1989; Series II
  - Writings
    - Articles
      - "Plasma Levels of Progestin During Absorption of Progesterone Pellets in Mice", 1958 (Box 22, Folder 131)
      - "Rapid Disappearance of Progesterone from Oily Solutions Injected Intraperitoneally in Mice", 1958 (Box 22, Folder 132)
      - "The Prediction of Sex: Folklore and Science", 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 133)
      - "Progestin in the Amniotic Fluids of Monkeys", 1958-1961 (Box 22, Folder 134)
      - "Reproduction in the Female" [in Medical Physiology and Biophysics ], 1958-1961 (Box 22, Folder 135)
      - "Word Charms and Amulets" [unpublished?], 1958-1965 (Box 22, Folder 136)
      - "Reproduction" [in Annual Review of Physiology, vol. 22], 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 137)
      - "Inactivation of Progesterone by Cellular Fractions of Rat Liver and Kidney in vitro" [with Alfred J. and Jane L. Coulombre], 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 138)
      - "Progestin in the Blood of Newborn Infants", 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 139)
      - "Intersexuality in Reptiles" [in Intersexuality in Vertebrates Including Man ], 1960-1964 (Box 22, Folder 140)
      - "Biologic Assay Methods" [in Progestins in Humans ], 1960-1967 (Box 22, Folder 141)
      - "The Local Action of Progesterone on Pregnant Uteri of Mice" [unpublished], 1961 (Box 23, Folder 142)
      - "Some Considerations of the Bio-Assay of Progestins" [in Brook Lodge Symposium on Progesterone ], 1961 (Box 23, Folder 143)
      - "John Hunter on Spontaneous Intersexuality", 1961-1964 (Box 23, Folder 144)
      - "Chalcedony and Childbirth: Precious and Semiprecious Stones as Obstetrical Amulets", 1962 (Box 23, Folder 145)
      - "Inactivation of Progesterone by Fetal Mouse Tissue in vitro" [with Alfred J. and Jane L. Coulombre], 1962 (Box 23, Folder 146)
      - "Perrette, the Midwife: A Fifteenth Century Witchcraft Case", 1962 (Box 23, Folder 147)
      - "Castration of Fish in the Eighteenth Century", 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 148)
      - "The Liberal Arts and the Premedical Student" [unpublished], 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 149)
      - "Maintenance of Pregnancy with Subcutaneous Pellets of Progesterone in Ovariectomized Mice" [with L. Rubinstein], 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 150)
      - "William Yarrell, British Naturalist", 1962-1970 (Box 23, Folder 151)
      - "Biological Inactivation by Binding to alpha-1 Acid Glycoprotein [Orosomucoid] [with U. Westphal], 1963 (Box 23, Folder 152)
      - "School of Medicine Admissions and Attrition", 1963 (Box 23, Folder 153)
      - "Thomas Fuller on What Makes a Doctor", 1963 (Box 23, Folder 154)
      - "Failure of 20α-Hydroxy-Pregnen-4-en-3-one to Maintain Pregnancy in Ovariectomized Mice" [with W. Weist], 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 155)
      - "Antagonisms and Synergisms in Progestin- Progestin Mixtures", 1964 (Box 23, Folder 156)
      - "Financial Problems of Medical Students", 1964 (Box 23, Folder 157)
      - "The Regulation of English Midwives in the Sixteenth and Seventeenth Centuries", 1964 (Box 23, Folder 158)
      - "Toxicity of Progesterone in Mouse Fetuses", 1964 (Box 23, Folder 159)
      - "Medical Lore in the Bestiaries", 1964-1970 (Box 23, Folder 160)
      - "Synergisms and Antagonisms of Estrogen and Progesterone in a Mouse Uterine Bio-Assay", 1966 (Box 23, Folder 161)
      - "Teaching the Anatomical and Physiological Aspects of Family Planning" [in Teaching Family Planning], 1966-1968 (Box 23, Folder 162)
      - "Progesterone,16α-Hydroxy Progesterones and the Maintenance of Pregnancy in Mice", 1967 (Box 23, Folder 163)
      - "Treatment of the Indigent Sick in a Nineteenth Century London Parish", 1967 (Box 23, Folder 164)
      - "Synergisms and Antagonisms of Testosterone: Progesterone and Estradiol-17β", 1968 (Box 23, Folder 165)
      - "Biological Inactivation of Progesterone by Interaction with Corticosteroid-Binding Globulin and with Albumin" [with W. Hoffman and U. Westphal], 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 166)
      - "Influence of 16α-Hydroxyprogesterone, 20α-Hydroxyprogesterone and 20β-Hydroxyprogesterone on Progesterone Activity in a Bio-Assay", 1970 (Box 23, Folder 167)
      - "Life and Death in Shakespeare's London", 1970 (Box 23, Folder 168)
      - "Maintenance of Pregnancy in Ovariectomized and Non-Ovariectomized Mice as an Index of Progesterone: Steroid Synergism and Antagonism", 1970 (Box 23, Folder 169)
      - "The Regulation of English Midwives in the Eighteenth and Nineteenth Centuries", 1970 (Box 23, Folder 170)
      - "Verbal Charms in British Folk Medicine", 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 171)
      - "Introduction" [in H. Thoms' Pioneers in Medicine at Yale ], 1971 (Box 23, Folder 172)
      - "Medical Supplies for Prisoners in 1675", 1972 (Box 23, Folder 173)
      - "Mortality Books for 1820 to 1949 from the Parish of St. Bride, Fleet", 1972 (Box 23, Folder 174)
      - "Sextons' Day Books for 1695-1687 and 1694-1703 from the Parish of St. Martin-in-the-Fields, London", 1972 (Box 23, Folder 175)
      - "Steroid Compounds and the Dilation of Ovarian and Uterine Veins in the Mouse", 1972 (Box 23, Folder 176)
      - "Steroid Compounds, Vasodilation, and Vasoconstriction in the Mouse", 1972 (Box 23, Folder 177)
      - "London Coroners' Inquests for 1590", 1973 (Box 23, Folder 178)
      - "A Note on the Procurement of Bodies for Dissection at the Royal College of Physicians of London in 1694 and 1710", 1973 (Box 23, Folder 179)
      - "Steroid Pellets and Venous Diameter in Orchidestomized, Ovariectomiized, and Ovariectomized-Hysterectomized Mice", 1973 (Box 24, Folder 180)
      - "Two New John Hunter Manuscripts", 1973 (Box 24, Folder 181)
      - "Burial Records of the Parish of St. Anne, Soho, London in 1814-1828", 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 182)
      - "The Madstone", 1973-1976 (Box 24, Folder 183)
      - "The Searchers", 1973-1976 (Box 24, Folder 184)
      - "Percival Pott Performs a Postmortem", 1974 (Box 24, Folder 185)
      - "Progesterone-Estrogen Antagonism in the Maintenance of Pregnancy in Ovariectomized Mice" [unpublished], 1974 (Box 24, Folder 186)
      - "16α-Hydroxy-Progesterone as a Sex Hormone Antagonist: Effect on Venous Diameters in the Female Mouse", 1974 (Box 24, Folder 187)
      - "Vein Size in Intact and Hysterectomized Mice During the Estrous Cycle and Pregnancy", 1974 (Box 24, Folder 188)
      - "Films Which Teach the History of Medicine", 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 189)
      - "Death of a Christian: A New William Hunter Manuscript", 1974-1976 (Box 24, Folder 190)
      - "Inquests into London and Middlesex Homicides, 1673-1792", 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 191)
      - "Why Is It Called 'Beautiful Lady'? A Note on Belladonna", 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 192)
      - "The Development of the Hooker-Forbes Assay", 1975 (Box 24, Folder 193)
      - "The Barber Surgeons Help the Sick Poor", 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 194)
      - "By What Disease or Casualty: The Changing Face of Death in London" [ Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences ], 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 195)
      - "A Mortality Record for Coldbath Fields Prison, London, 1795-1829", 1976 (Box 24, Folder 196)
      - "Specific Response of Ovarian and Uterine Veins of Mice to Sex Hormones", 1976 (Box 24, Folder 197)
      - "Malpractice and Manslaughter: The Case of Martin Van Butchell", 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 198)
      - "Apprentice in Trouble: Some Problems in the Training of Surgeons and Apothecaries in Seventeenth Century London", 1976-1979 (Box 24, Folder 199)
      - "The Case of the Quarrelsome Watchman" [with Joan L. Venes], 1977 (Box 24, Folder 200)
      - "Coroner's Inquest in the County of Middlesex, England, 1819-42", 1977 (Box 24, Folder 201)
      - "An Early Record of a Freemartin", 1977-1979 (Box 24, Folder 202)
      - "The Case of the Casual Chirurgeon", 1978 (Box 24, Folder 203)
      - "Coroners' Inquisitions on the Deaths of Prisoners in the Hulks at Portsmouth, England in 1817-1827", 1978 (Box 24, Folder 204)
      - "Weaver and Cordwainer in the Parish of St. Giles Without Cripplegate, London, in 1654-1693 and 1729-1743", 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 205)
      - "Births and Deaths in a London Parish. The Record from the Registers, 1654-1693 and 1729-1743", 1979-1981, undated (Box 24, Folder 206)
      - "By What Disease or Casualty: The Changing Face of Death in London" [chapter in Health, Medicine, and Mortality in the Sixteenth Century ], 1980 (Box 24, Folder 207)
      - "John Hunter as Expert Witness", 1980 (Box 24, Folder 208)
      - "When Did Lionel Wafer Die?", 1980 (Box 24, Folder 209)
      - "Early Forensic Medicine in England: The Angus Murder Trial", 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 210)
      - "A Study of Old Bailey Sentences between 1729 and 1800", 1980-1981, undated (Box 25, Folder 211)
      - "A Quack in Court", 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folder 212)
      - "Coroners' Inquisitions", 1983 (Box 25, Folder 213)
      - "Mortality at St. Bartholomew's Hospital, London, 1839-1872", 1983 (Box 25, Folder 214)
      - "Term Taming for Medical Students" [unpublished?], 1984-1987 (Box 25, Folder 215)
      - "Deadly Parents: Child Homicide in Eighteenth and Nineteenth Century England", 1985 (Box 25, Folder 216)
      - "Death and the Debtors: Mortality in a Nineteenth Century London Prison", 1985-1987 (Box 25, Folder 217)
      - "Coroners' Inquisitions from the County Cheshire, England, 1817-1839 and 1877-1878", 1985-1988 (Box 25, Folder 218)
      - "Surgeons in Court"; "Caul" [entry for Encyclopedia of American Popular Beliefs and Superstitions ], 1986 (Box 25, Folder 219)
      - "A Jury of Matrons", 1987 (Box 25, Folder 220)
      - "Coroners' Inquisitions from London Parishes of the Duchy of Lancaster, the Strand, Clapham, Enfield, and Edmonton. 1831-1883", 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 221)
    - Articles, shorter, 1980-1984 (Box 25, Folder 222)
    - Book reviews, 1946-1988 (Box 25, Folder 223 - 225)
    - Books
      - The Midwife and the Witch
        - General, 1964-1966 (Box 26, Folder 226)
        - Post-publication correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 227)
        - Radio broadcast, reviews, 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 228)
      - Chronicle from Aldgate, 1967-1978 (Box 26, Folder 229)
      - Web of Days, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 230)
      - Crowner's Quest (Box 26)
        - General, 1971-1977 (Box 26, Folder 231)
        - American Philosophical Society, 1976-1979 (Box 26, Folder 232)
        - Other publishers, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 233)
        - Reviews, 1979-1981 (Box 26, Folder 234)
      - The Admirable Secrets of Physick and Chyrurgery by Thomas Palmer, [Edited by Forbes] II, 1979-1986 (Box 26, Folder 235 - 236)
      - "Scalpels for Justice" [unpublished], 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 237)
      - Surgeons of the Bailey (Box 26)
        - Reviews, 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 238)
        - Yale Press, 1982-1987 (Box 26, Folder 239 - 240)
    - Short stories, 1987-1989 (Box 27, Folder 241)
    - Films
      - General
        - Funding applications, 1969-1977 (Box 27, Folder 242 - 243)
        - Inquiries, showings, distribution, 1972-1979 (Box 27, Folder 244)
        - Promotion, 1972-1978, undated (Box 27, Folder 245)
      - John Hunter, the Enlightened Empiricist, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 246)
      - Vesalius, Founder of Modern Anatomy, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 247)
      - Ambrose Paré, Military Surgeon, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 248)
      - The Resurrectionists, 1976-1987 (Box 27, Folder 249 - 250)
    - Lectures
      - France ["L'Intersexualité Chez les Reptiles," "Quelques Observations sur la Physiologie de Progestérone" and "Quelques Observations sur le Métabolisme de Progestérone"], 1950 (Box 28, Folder 251)
      - Germany [United Services Mission], 1950 (Box 28, Folder 252 - 254)
      - Discussion at Laurentian Hormone Conference of paper by M. E. Davis and E. J. Flotz, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 255)
      - "Is There Time for Both?", 1962 (Box 28, Folder 256)
      - "Estrogen, Progesterone, Synergisms and Antagonisms" [notes], 1966 (Box 28, Folder 257)
      - "Life and Death in Shakespeare's London" [various venues], 1969-1975 (Box 28, Folder 258)
      - Gideon de Laune Lecture, Society of Apothecaries, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 259)
      - "Anatomists and Physiologists of the Renaissance" [Uniformed Services University School of Medicine], 1976 (Box 28, Folder 260)
      - "Lionel Wafer, the Private Surgeon", 1980 (Box 28, Folder 261)
      - "The Profile of Death in a London Parish", 1981 (Box 28, Folder 262)
      - "Don't Bring That Up Again" [Yale Medical Alumni], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 263)
      - "Mason Cogswell Goes to Yale", 1981 (Box 28, Folder 264)
      - "Infanticide and Early English Forensic Medicine" [History of Medicine, Yale and Johns Hopkins], 1982 (Box 28, Folder 265)
      - Seminar talk [Yale Medical Class of 1958], 1983 (Box 28, Folder 266)
      - "Early Forensic Medicine in London", 1984 (Box 28, Folder 267)
      - "Midwifery and Superstition", 1985 (Box 28, Folder 268)
      - "Midwifery and Witchcraft", 1985 (Box 28, Folder 269)
      - "Surgeons in Court: John Hunter and Forensic Medicine", 1985 (Box 28, Folder 270)
      - "Early Infanticide and Child Homicide in England", 1986 (Box 28, Folder 271)
      - Panel discussion on AIDS, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 272)
      - "Comments on the Hippocratic Oath", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 273)
      - "The Doctor on the Witness Stand", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 274)
      - "Looking at Ourselves", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 275)
      - "Midwifery in Eighteenth Century England", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 276)
      - "Early English Forensic Medicine", [1987?] (Box 28, Folder 277)
    - Tributes to professional colleagues, 1961-1973 (Box 28, Folder 278)
- Personal Papers, 1930-1988; Series III
  This series contains documentation of honors and tributes, memorabilia of trips abroad, clippings, and photographs of professional colleagues and groups. The files of personal annual reports are a useful record of Forbes's professional accomplishments. These were probably submitted for the compilation of university departmental reports and include partial bibliographies of Forbes's writings.
  - Army-Navy Certificate of Appreciation, 191948 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 191960, 1966, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Foreign travel, 191950-1985 (Box 29, Folder 3 - 5)
  - Photographs [professional colleagues and groups], 191930s-1980s (Box 29, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Yale School of Medicine
    - Annual reports, 191945-1988 (Box 29, Folder 8 - 10)
    - Sabbatical leaves, 191965, 1970, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Reception honoring Forbes, 191969 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Student theses, in the history of medicine supervised by Forbes [list, 1954-1974], 191975 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - George Rosen Prize in the History of Medicine, 191977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Ebenezer K. Hunt Professorship, 191977-1983 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Visitors to Forbes's laboratory [list], 191948-1964 (Box 29, Folder 16)